SUMMARY

I am a **Software Engineer** with 7+ years of professional experience and a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I am currently working for **WeWork** on the Space squad(in **Core-platform**) building backend services (which deals with the spatial data for all the Wework's buildings) and few components of ingestion pipeline that transforms the raw Revit model's data and stores them into our relational datastore for better query-ability serving various business needs. I have decent knowledge of microservices, observability stack, databases, algorithms, data structures, and distributed systems.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer WeWork Oct 2018 till present

- Worked on a team of 5 engineers building/managing various apps and services across the core-platform which
 deals with ingestion-pipeline and our source-of-truth backend service which holds all the spatial data that
 Wework has supporting use cases like Inventory management, Occupancy Map visualization, etc.
- Contributed to re-writing a legacy application to a Go/gRPC/Protobuff based tech stack and addressing the performance concerns of our legacy app. This involved re-designing our query patterns across all endpoints. We were able to bring down the latencies from over few seconds to 100ms for P99 requests.
- Benchmarking (Load-testing) and tuning the database configurations on both database and application side for dealing with the performance bottlenecks.
- Implemented Observability (logging, monitoring, tracing, and grafana dashboards) across various services.
- Experience working with Kafka backed event-driven system for various business needs. Used Apache Avro for data serialization and schema registry for schema enforcements for the events sent to Kafka.
- Experience working in cross-functional teams and various working groups across core-platform.
- Experience working in **Agile (Scrum)** doing backlog grooming, retrospective meetings, Iteration Planning with engineering and product managers for focusing on team priorities and growth. Experience with Jira and Trello.
- **Technologies Used:** Go, gRPC, Kafka, Protocol buffers, Avro, Postgres, Vault, Kubernetes, Docker-compose, Log entries, Jaeger, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, Helmfile, Makefile, CircleCl, etc.

I.T. Analyst Tata Consultancy Services June 2012-Oct 2018

- Worked as a backend developer for CVS on various apps including their core enterprise pharmacy application deployed across all the stores in USA and other web apps.
- Wrote REST based web services, Multi-threaded high-performance Java Batches, JMS transactions for interactions with other systems within CVS. Also, designing data model and implementing Secure Login API (Security standards around username/password functionality for the web app).
- Held a position of **DevOps** engineer for a couple of months managing setting up the dev-prod environments hosted on Openstack, writing **Chef** Scripts for infra-automation (httpd, and tomcat installation/configuration).
- Implement CI/CD **Jenkins** pipeline for various applications within CVS that resulted in faster deploy and feedback cycles across applications. Saved 30% of Dev/QA's effort.
- Developed backend of a dashboard web-app and migrated the environment data from multiple excel sheets to single dashboard app resulting in reduced error rates for the Ops team.
- Conducted sessions within the team regarding the latest DevOps adoptions.
- **Technologies Used:** Java, Spring boot, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Apache HTTP Server, Tomcat, Weblogic, MariaDB, REST, GIT/SVN, ANT/Maven, Oracle, MySQL, Chef, Jenkins etc.

EDUCATION

NIT Jalandhar July 2008 – June 2012

- Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech) in Computer Science, 2012, CGPA: 7.41/10
- Core undergraduate subjects: Operating Systems, Databases, Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Distributed Systems, and Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Compilers etc.